Mss.Ms.Coll.109
American Philosophical Society
Ashley Montagu papers, 1927-1999
Mss.Ms.Coll.109
American Philosophical Society
57.0 Linear feet
Ashley Montagu (1905-1999), physical anthropologist, was a prominent figure in American intellectual life. British by birth, educated at University College London and the London School of Economics, then Columbia University in New York City, Montagu was a persistent advocate for gender and racial equality. He was a tireless activist for human understanding and child welfare in particular. Departing from academe in 1955, a victim of McCarthyite hysteria, he was a remarkably prolific writer and speaker, eventually publishing more than 50 books, over 40 of them after he left the academy. Montagu continued to lobby passionately against the primacy of race in discussions of intellect and skill, and undertook works in a wide variety of fields, from evolution to parenting. Some of his most significant works include Man's Most Dangerous Myth: The Fallacy of Race (1942), the UNESCO Statement on Race (1951), Man and Aggression (1968) and his novel The Elephant Man (1971), which became the basis for an award winning play and movie. Ashley Montagu’s contributions to the spread of scientific knowledge and human understanding make him one of the most important intellectuals of the 20th century.
55.75 linear feet.
Abbie,, Andrew Arthur, 1905-1976
Askenasy, Hans, 1930-
Benton, William, 1900-1973
Boas, Franz, 1858-1942
Briffault, Robert
Buhler, Charlotte, 1983-1974
Carpenter, Edmund, 1922-2011
Clark, Wilfrid E. Le Gros, (Wilfrid Edward Le Gros), 1895-1971
Dobzhansky, Theodosius Grigorievich, 1900-1975
Einstein, Albert, 1879-1955
Eisler, Riane Tennenhaus
Elkin, A. P. (Adolphus Peter), 1891-1979
Evans, Bergen, 1904-1978
Freeman, Derek
Fromm, Erich,1900-1980
Goldstein, Marcus Solomon
Gould, Stephen Jay
Keith, Arthur, Sir, 1866-1955
Kluckhohn, Clyde, 1905-1960
La Barre, Weston, 1911-1996
Matson, Floyd W.
McLuhan, Marshall, 1911-1980
Meade, Margaret, 1901-1978
Montagu, Ashley, 1905-1999
Oakley, Kenneth Page, 1911
Sarton, George, 1884-1956
Sorokin, Pitirim Aleksandrovich, 1889-1968
Yerkes, Robert Mearns, 1876-1956
Biographical/Historical note
Ashley Montagu, born Israel Ehrenberg on June 28, 1905, was a British-American anthropologist, specializing in the areas of race and gender issues, as well as a prolific speaker and author, publishing over 50 books in his lifetime. The son of Jewish tailor Charles Ehrenberg and his wife, Mary Plot Ehrenberg, Montagu was born and raised in London's working class East End neighborhood. Although the reasoning behind his name change was never revealed, it may have been due to anti-Semitic prejudice faced by many East End Jews during his childhood, and Montagu might have felt the need to distance himself from his parents’ Russian and Polish backgrounds.
Montagu earned his undergraduate degree from University College London in psychology and anthropology. After studying anthropology at the London School of Economics under Bronislaw Malinowski, Montagu left England for the United States. He arrived at New York City in 1927 and began taking graduate classes at Columbia University. Montagu then traveled to Italy in 1928, where he took classes in ethnography and anthropology at the University of Florence. Upon his return to the United States in 1931, while working as an assistant professor of anthropology at New York University, Montagu married Marjorie Peakes. The couple would have two daughters, Audrey and Barbara, as well as a son, Geoffrey. In 1934 Montagu returned to Columbia University, culminating his postgraduate work at Columbia in 1936 with his dissertation, Coming into being among the Australian Aborigines: A study of the procreative beliefs of the native tribes of Australia, produced under the direction of Franz Boas and Ruth Benedict. Based largely on his dissertation, Montagu’s first book, Coming into Being among the Australian Aborigines, was published in 1937. After he completed his education, Montagu taught anatomy at Hahnemann Medical College in Philadelphia in 1938 and became an American citizen in 1940. It was during his time at Hahnemann that he began to produce work relating to race, resulting in his seminal work, Man's Most Dangerous Myth: The Fallacy of Race, published in 1942. The work controversially advanced the argument that race was a social construct imposed upon a complex biological substratum and demolished the arguments for inherent inequality between human populations. The influential nature of Man’s Most Dangerous Myth led to Montagu’s service on the 4th United Nations Educational, Scientific, and Cultural Organization (UNESCO) task force, in 1949. The ten member UNESCO committee, composed of such world-renowned social scientists as Claude Levi-Strauss and E. Franklin Frazier, was created to collect information about the problem of race and to establish educational programs to disseminate its findings. The resultant document, authored by Montagu, the group’s rapporteur, was published as the “Statement on Race” in 1951. The Committee’s final statement on race asserted: 1)All mankind belong to the same species and that the differences between groups are few compared to all of the genetic similarities. 2)That Race designates a group with high frequency of physical characteristics or particular genetic trait and that these traits fluctuate or even disappear over time. 3)The way in which people are grouped does not reflect the capacity or character traits of a particular group. The differences between races are physical and have no correlation with other traits like intelligence.
Upon leaving Hahnemann Medical College in 1949, Montagu moved to Rutgers University, where he was a professor of anthropology and head of the department from 1949 to 1955. While at Rutgers, Montagu wrote perhaps his most famous work, The Natural Superiority of Women, published in 1953. Examining the differences between the sexes anthropologically, Montagu concluded that women were the superior sex because they possessed a better capability to survive both as individuals and in groups- talents necessary for an advancing society. Based on these conclusions, he suggested that women receive equal pay for equal work, a controversial stance at the time.
With his prolific writing skills to rely on financially, and facing strong backlash for his openly liberal views and anti-McCarthy public statements, Montagu accepted a forced retirement from Rutgers in 1955 at the age of 50. Though retired from academic life, he continued to lecture at such institutions as Harvard University, Princeton University, the University of Santa Barbara, and New York University. Settling in Princeton, New Jersey, Montagu’s work took up a more humanist element with Touching: The Human Significance of the Skin, his effort to encourage parents to take a more physical role in raising their children and especially to encourage mothers to breastfeed their babies. Published during that same year, Montagu’s book The Elephant Man: A Study in Human Dignity, a history of the life of disfigured Briton Joseph Merrick, inspired a Tony winning play and later a motion picture. He continued publishing through the 1980s, including The Nature of Human Aggression (1976) and Growing Young (1981), while making numerous and notable television appearances on Johnny Carson’s Tonight Show as well as the Phil Donahue Show.
In his lifetime, Montagu received many major awards, among them the American Association of Humanists’ 1995 Man of the Year award, the Darwin Award from the American Association of Physical Anthropologist in 1994, and the Distinguished Achievement Award from the American Anthropological Association in 1987. Montagu maintained an active schedule of lecturing and gardening around his Princeton, New Jersey, home until he was hospitalized in March 1999; he died on November 26, 1999 from heart disease, at the age of ninety-four. He was survived by his wife of sixty-eight years, Marjorie, as well as his son and two daughters.
Immediate Source of Acquisition note
Acquired from the Montagu estate, July 2001.
Scope and Contents note
The collection documents Ashley Montagu’s entire career from 1927 to 1999. The collection consists of 55.75 linear feet of material, organized into twelve series, plus oversize. Nearly half of the collection is Montagu’s correspondence with colleagues, publishers, coauthors, and intellectuals from almost every discipline, as well as admirers from many different walks of life. There also several complete manuscripts of Montagu’s work including The Natural Superiority of Women, The Elephant Man, and The Anatomy of Swearing, as well as numerous journal and magazine articles authored by Montagu. The collection reflects the range of Montagu’s intellectual interest and his influence across the spectrum of academic disciplines over his 60 year career. The collection was acquired from the Montagu estate in July 2001.
Arrangement Series I- Correspondence (25.25 linear feet) Series II- Correspondence with Publishers (3.5 linear feet) Series III- Works by Montagu (12.75 linear feet) Series IV- Media Appearances (1.25 linear feet) Series V- Princeton (0.5 linear feet) Series VI- Works by Others (5 linear feet) Series VII- Committees and Organizations (1.75 linear feet) Series VIII- Certificates and Awards (0.25 linear feet) Series IX- Personal Information (0.5 linear feet) Series X- Printed Materials (3 linear feet) Series XI- Photographs (1.5 linear feet) Series XII- Recordings (0.5 linear feet)
African American History Note
Scholars of African American history will find much useful information on the subject of race in this collection.
Anthropology; Anthropology, ethnography, fieldwork; Biology, genetics, eugenics; Gender; Race, race relations, racism; Race.; Social conditions, social advocacy, social reform; Social inequality
- Correspondence, 25.25 linear feet
  Scope and Contents note
  Series I consists of Ashley Montagu’s correspondence with various colleagues and scholars over the course of his entire professional life, as well as correspondence with friends and fans. Of particular interest is his correspondence with Theodosius Dobzhansky, Bronislaw Malinowski, and Albert Einstein. There are four letters to Montagu from Einstein and copies of Montagu’s responses. The bulk of the correspondence is incoming.
  - Abbie, A.A, 1953-1964; 5 items (Box 1)
  - Abbot, Charles, 1950; 2 items (Box 1)
  - D U M M Y
  - Academic Recording Institute, 1959; 1 item (Box 1)
  - Acheson, Nancy, 1981; 1 item (Box 1)
  - Ackerknecht, Erwin, 1946; 1 item (Box 1)
  - Adams, Ansel, 1966-1976; 3 item (Box 1)
  - Adams, Daniel, 1968; 1 item (Box 1)
  - Adams, David, 1979-1986; 19 items (Box 1)
  - Adams, Deanna, 1991; 1 item 1 (Box 1)
  - Adams, Frances, 1969; 1 item (Box 1)
  - Adams, Gordon, 1991; 1 item (Box 1)
  - Adams, John, 1972; 1 item (Box 1)
  - Adams, Mary, 1966; 1987; 2 items (Box 1)
  - Adams, Phyllis, undated; 1 item (Box 1)
  - Adams, Robert, 1951; 1 item (Box 1)
  - Adams, Ruth, 1971; 1 item (Box 1)
  - Adams, Taylor, undated; 1 item (Box 1)
  - Adcock, Joe, 1969; 1 item (Box 1)
  - Adelberg, Michael, 1986; 1990-1996; 13 items (Box 1)
  - Adelman, Bob, undated; 1 item (Box 1)
  - Adler, Alexander, 1970; 1 item (Box 1)
  - Adler, Elmer, 1936; 4 items (Box 1)
  - Adler, Michael, 1983; 1 item (Box 1)
  - Adwokat, Nancy, 1982; 1 item (Box 1)
  - Aedy, Edna, 1976; 1 item (Box 1)
  - Agathos, Barbara, 1969; 1 item (Box 1)
  - Agogino, George, 1959-1965; 3 items (Box 1)
  - Agonito, Rosemary, 1979; 1 item (Box 1)
  - Ahlstrom, Cyndie, 1981; 1 item (Box 1)
  - Aiello, Valeria, 1977; 3 items (Box 1)
  - Aiken, Charlotte, 1954-1967; undated; 16 items (Box 1)
  - Aiken, William, 1948; 1 item (Box 1)
  - Ainsworth, Jerry, 1993; undated; 2 items (Box 1)
  - Akeley, Barton, 1964; 1 item (Box 1)
  - Akiyama, Tomiya, 1979; 1 item (Box 1)
  - Alatriste, Irma, 1977; 1 item (Box 1)
  - Alben, Ruth, 1988; 1 item (Box 1)
  - Aldington, Richard, 1943-1944; 4 items (Box 1)
  - Aldrich, Robert, 1963; 1 item (Box 1)
  - Aldridge, John, 1955-1966; 12 items (Box 1)
  - Alexander, Jason, 1981; 1 item (Box 1)
  - Alexander, N.E, 1976; 2 items (Box 1)
  - Alexander, Rae Pace, 1965; 1 item (Box 1)
  - Alexander, Richard, 1975-1978; 23 items (Box 1)
  - Aley Associates, 1961-1963; undated; 30 items (Box 1)
  - Alford, John, 1950; 1 item (Box 1)
  - Aligica, Paul Dragos, 1992; 1 item (Box 1)
  - Alison, Henry, 1969; 1 item (Box 1)
  - Allard, Gerold, 1988; 1 item (Box 1)
  - Allee, W.C, 1949-1951; 4 items (Box 1)
  - Allen, Deanna, 1993; 1 item (Box 1)
  - Allen, Edna, 1983; 1 item (Box 1)
  - Allen, John MD, 1972; 1 item (Box 1)
  - Allen, Richard Hobcraft, 1976; 1 item (Box 1)
  - Allen, Robert, 1983; 1 item (Box 1)
  - Allen, Steve, 1986; 1 item (Box 1)
  - Allerand, C. Dominique, 1964; 1 item (Box 1)
  - Allison, Clive, 1983; 1 item (Box 1)
  - Allport, Gordon, 1946; 1 item (Box 1)
  - Alvarez, Walter, 1993; 1 item (Box 1)
  - Amemiya, Tsuyoshi, 1970-1987; 149 items (Box 1)
  - Amemiya, Tsuyoshi, 1988-1998; 95 items (Box 1)
  - Amis, Kingsley, 1959; undated; 2 items (Box 2)
  - Amorde, Eric, 1982; 1 item (Box 2)
  - Amory, Cleveland, 1966; 1 item (Box 2)
  - Anagnosti, John, 1981-1982; undated; 14 items (Box 2)
  - Andersen, Jim and Susan, 1987-1992; undated; 22 items (Box 2)
  - Anderson, Caroline, 1977; 1 item (Box 2)
  - Anderson, Ian, 1971; 1 item (Box 2)
  - Anderson, Joyce Sloan, 1971; 1 item (Box 2)
  - Anderson, Nancy, undated; 1 item (Box 2)
  - Anderson, Robert C, 1983; 2 items (Box 2)
  - Anderson, Robert, 1954; 3 items (Box 2)
  - Anderson, Susan, 1993; 1994; 2 items (Box 2)
  - Andreski, L, 1981; 1 item (Box 2)
  - Andrews, Allison, 1989; 1 item (Box 2)
  - Andrews, Duncan, 1974; 1 item (Box 2)
  - Angel, 1981-1985; undated; 6 items (Box 2)
  - Angel, J. Lawrence, 1946-1966; 2 items (Box 2)
  - Angell, James, 1942; 2 items (Box 2)
  - Angers, Trent, 1980; 1981; 4 items (Box 2)
  - Angier, Natalie, 1990; 1 item (Box 2)
  - Angstadt, Bill, 1981; 1 item (Box 2)
  - Angyan, Andre, 1976; 1 item (Box 2)
  - Ansbacher, Heinz, 1963-1976; 10 items (Box 2)
  - Anshen, Ruth, 1949; 2 items (Box 2)
  - Anthoney, Josephine, 1975; 1976; 2 items (Box 2)
  - Anti-Defamation League, 1989; 1994; 11 items (Box 2)
  - Apgar, Virginia, 1961; 7 items (Box 2)
  - Appel, Kenneth, 1955; 1 item (Box 2)
  - Appell, Lynda, 1982; 1 item (Box 2)
  - Apple Computers, 1992; 1993; 4 items (Box 2)
  - Applegate, Howard, 1967-1971; 9 items (Box 2)
  - Appleman, Phillip, 1967-1993; 4 items (Box 2)
  - Apsey, Virginia, 1981; 1 item (Box 2)
  - Arber, Agnes, 1943-1947; 2 items (Box 2)
  - Arcide, Kathie, undated; 1 item (Box 2)
  - Ardito, Mary, 1979; 1 item (Box 2)
  - Ardrey, Robert, 1961-1969; 3 items (Box 2)
  - Arenader, Alaric, 1989; 3 items (Box 2)
  - Arendt, Hannah, 1945-1951; 4 items (Box 2)
  - Arey, Leslie, 1961; 1 item (Box 2)
  - Arieti, Silvano, 1977; 1 item (Box 2)
  - Armstrong, A.J, 1931; 2 items (Box 2)
  - Armstrong, Arthur, 1982; 1 item (Box 2)
  - Armstrong, J. Scott, 1979; 1 item (Box 2)
  - Armstrong, Thomas, 1990; 1 item (Box 2)
  - Arnold, Melvin, 1959; 1 item (Box 2)
  - Arnovitz, Benton, 1972; 1990; 2 items (Box 2)
  - Arruth, Stanley, undated; 1 item (Box 2)
  - Arthur, Jean, 1949; 2 items (Box 2)
  - Ashley, Horace, 1976; 1 item (Box 2)
  - Asimov, Isaac, 1986; 1 item (Box 2)
  - Askanasy, Hans, 1997; undated; 2 items (Box 2)
  - Aski, Candace, 1979; 1 item (Box 2)
  - Aslwonder, Donald, 1976; 1 item (Box 2)
  - Aubrey, J.S, 1978; 1 item (Box 2)
  - Augusta, G.M, 1982; 1 item (Box 2)
  - Auper, R.H, 1939; 1 item (Box 2)
  - Ausenda, Giorgio, 1977; 1 item (Box 2)
  - Austin-Leigh, Joan, 1979; 1 item (Box 2)
  - Avedon, Burt, 1978; 1 item (Box 2)
  - Avery, Jimmie Lynne, 1977-1978; 5 items (Box 2)
  - Avery, Mary Ellen, 1985; 1 item (Box 2)
  - Ayana, Giselle, 1996; 1 item (Box 2)
  - Aydelotte, Frank, 1943; 1 item (Box 2)
  - Ayochok, William, 1982; 1 item (Box 2)
  - Ayodele, F, 1971; 1 item (Box 2)
  - Ayres, Hester Merwin, 1967; undated; 2 items (Box 2)
  - Ayres, Lew, 1968-1997; undated; 20 items (Box 2)
  - A-Misc, 1968-1990; 20 items (Box 2)
  - B-Misc, 1943-1996; 39 items (Box 6)
  - Baby Lamb Products, 1982; 1 item (Box 3)
  - Bacard, Andre, undated; 1 item (Box 3)
  - Bachrach, Fabian, 1979; 1 item (Box 3)
  - Badal, Robert S, 1985; 1987; 4 items (Box 4)
  - Bailey, Herbert, 1963; 1 item (Box 3)
  - Bailey, Janet, 1976; 1992; 2 items (Box 3)
  - Bailey, Percival, 1961; 2 items (Box 3)
  - Bain, Bruce, 1980; 2 items (Box 3)
  - Bair, Bruce, 1967; 5 items (Box 3)
  - Baird, Emily, 1980; 1 item (Box 3)
  - Bakelaar, George, 1992; 1 item (Box 3)
  - Baker, Deborah, 1982; 1 item (Box 3)
  - Bakunas, Keith, 1982; 2 items (Box 3)
  - Balaam, John, 1982; 1 item (Box 3)
  - Baldwin, Christy, 1991; 1 item (Box 3)
  - Bale, John, 1930; 2 items (Box 3)
  - Ballantine, Ian, 1953; 1 item (Box 3)
  - Ballif, Marie, 1978; 1 item (Box 3)
  - Balogh, G, 1979; 1 item (Box 3)
  - Balogh, Penelope, 1972-1974; 3 items (Box 3)
  - Band, Henretta, 1978; 1 item (Box 3)
  - Banerjee, Dinabandhu, 1971; 1 item (Box 3)
  - Banks, Max, 1969; 1 item (Box 3)
  - Barba, Rose Marie, 1984; 1 item (Box 3)
  - Barba, William, 1974; 1 item (Box 3)
  - Barber, Charles, 1981; 1 item (Box 3)
  - Barber, Edwin, 1989; 1 item (Box 3)
  - Barbush, Elizabeth, 1973; 1 item (Box 3)
  - Barkley, Bill, undated; 1 item (Box 3)
  - Barlow, F.O, 1929, 1936; 2 items (Box 3)
  - Barnard, Kathryn, 1990; 1 item (Box 3)
  - Barnes, Catherine, 1989; 1 item (Box 3)
  - Barnes, Leo, 1978; 1 item (Box 3)
  - Barnett, Paul, 1982; 1 item (Box 3)
  - Barnett, S.A, 1957-1987; 8 items (Box 3)
  - Barnett, Steve, 1988; 1 item (Box 3)
  - Barnhart, Clarence, 1950; 1 item (Box 3)
  - Barnicot, N.A, 1959-1960; 3 items (Box 3)
  - Barr, Murray, 1958; 3 items (Box 3)
  - Barr, Rod, 1986-1989; 10 items (Box 3)
  - Barraclough, Geoffrey, 1975; 2 item (Box 3)
  - Barrett, Reginald, 1950; 2 items (Box 3)
  - Barron, Louise, 1988; 4 items (Box 3)
  - Barrus, Cherril, 1977; 1 item (Box 3)
  - Barry, Harriet, 1977; 2 items (Box 3)
  - Bartalos, Mihaly, 1968-1972; 4 items (Box 3)
  - Bartell, Shirley, 1965; 1 item (Box 3)
  - Bartemeier, Leo, 1950; 1 item (Box 3)
  - Baruch, Dorothy, 1952-1961; 3 items (Box 3)
  - Basco, Sharon, 1977; 1 item (Box 3)
  - Basiuk, Victor, 1972, 1977; 2 items (Box 3)
  - Bass, Harry, 1988; 6 items (Box 3)
  - Bates, Marston, 1951; 1952; 2 items (Box 3)
  - Bates, Roy, 1966; 1 item (Box 3)
  - Bateson, Gregory, 1946-1983; 5 items (Box 3)
  - Bateson, Patrick, 1958; 1 item (Box 3)
  - Baudhuin, Scott, 1969; 1 item (Box 3)
  - Bauer, Myra, 1983; 2 items (Box 3)
  - Baum, Carolyn Manville, 1982; 1 item (Box 3)
  - Bax, Martin, 1970-1971; 4 items (Box 3)
  - Bayles, Martha, 1981; 2 items (Box 3)
  - Bayless, William, 1971; 1 item (Box 3)
  - Beaglehole, Ernest, 1946; 1 item (Box 3)
  - Beaham, Cathy, 1977; 3 items (Box 3)
  - Beals, Kenneth, 1978; 2 items (Box 3)
  - Beatty, Jerome, undated; 1 item (Box 3)
  - Beaver, Charlie, 1983; 1 item (Box 3)
  - Beck, Cameron, 1984; 1 item (Box 3)
  - Beck, John R, 1977; 1 item (Box 3)
  - Becker, Jean, 1989; 1 item (Box 3)
  - Bedford, Sybille, 1968; 6 items (Box 3)
  - Beebe, Richard M, 1969; 1 item (Box 3)
  - Behan, Thomas D, 1968; 1 item (Box 3)
  - Behner, Seth, 1995; 2 items (Box 3)
  - Belew, Louise, 1969; 4 items (Box 3)
  - Belfiore, Gerardo, 1990-1997; 3 items (Box 3)
  - Belknap, Marty, 1981; 2 items (Box 3)
  - Bell, John, 1988; 1 item (Box 3)
  - Bell, Kathy, 1980; 1 item (Box 3)
  - Bellugi, Ursula, 1975; 1 item (Box 3)
  - Belmont, Thomas, 1978; 1979; 2 items (Box 3)
  - Belshaw, Cyril, 1977-1982; 5 items (Box 3)
  - Ben-Israel, Ady, 1995; 2 items (Box 3)
  - Bender, Bob, 1987; 1 item (Box 3)
  - Bender, Michael, 1959-1961; 7 items (Box 3)
  - Benedict, Gail, 1971; 1 item (Box 3)
  - Benedict, Ruth, 1936-1944; 4 items (Box 3)
  - Bengsten, June, 1981; 1 item (Box 3)
  - Benirschke, Kurt, 1962; 1963; 2 items (Box 3)
  - Benjamin, Jack, 1951; 1 item (Box 3)
  - Bennefelo, Judy, 1977; 1 item (Box 3)
  - Bennett, Jeanne, 1959; 2 items (Box 3)
  - Bennet, Jessica, 1964; 1 item (Box 3)
  - Bennett, Lynn, 1976; 1 items (Box 3)
  - Bennett, William, 1970-1984; 1 item (Box 3)
  - Benton, William, 1970-1973; 28 items (Box 3)
  - Bergen, Bernard, 1965; 2 items (Box 4)
  - Berger, F.M, 1965-1971; 8 items (Box 4)
  - Berger, Peter, 1969; 1 item (Box 4)
  - Bergin, James, 1978; undated; 3 items (Box 4)
  - Bergland, Richard, 1989; 1 item (Box 4)
  - Bergler, Edmund, 1945; 2 items (Box 4)
  - Bergsoe, Paul, 1938; 1 item (Box 4)
  - Bergson, Peter, 1985-1995; 6 items (Box 4)
  - Berlin, Isaiah, 1954; 1 item (Box 4)
  - Berman, Alice, 1982; 2 items (Box 4)
  - Berman, Morris, 1989; 3 items (Box 4)
  - Berman, Phillip, 1983-1989; 27 items (Box 4)
  - Bermann, Sandra, undated; 1 item (Box 4)
  - Berndt, Ronald, 1947-1980; 6 items (Box 4)
  - Bernheimer, Gladys, 1952; 1 item (Box 4)
  - Bernheimer, Richard, March 16; 1 item (Box 4)
  - Bernikow, Louise, 1985; 1 item (Box 4)
  - Berrill, John, 1958-1991; 8 items (Box 4)
  - Berry, Madeleine, 1969; 1 item (Box 4)
  - Berzins, Mirdza Erika, 1991; 1 item (Box 4)
  - Best, Geoffrey, 1988; 1 item (Box 4)
  - Best, Jerry, 1989; 1 item (Box 4)
  - Bettelheim, Bruno, 1954-1968; 3 items (Box 4)
  - Bhaumik, M.C, 1988-1998; 6 items (Box 4)
  - Bianco, Lori, 1987; 1 item (Box 4)
  - Bielenson, Peter, 1936; undated; 2 items (Box 4)
  - Bijur, Marion, 1953; 1 item (Box 4)
  - Bijur, Victoria, 1979; 1 item (Box 4)
  - Bingham, Wheelock H, 1968; 3 items (Box 4)
  - Binus, Emily, 1981; 1 item (Box 4)
  - Bird, Caroline, 1958; 1 item (Box 4)
  - Bird, E.B, 1943; 1 item (Box 4)
  - Birdsell, Joseph, 1961; 1 item (Box 4)
  - Birdwhistell, Ray, 1969; 1 item (Box 4)
  - Birenbaum, William, 1964-1983; 7 items (Box 4)
  - Birx, James, 1988; 1992; 2 items (Box 4)
  - Bishop, Becky, 1978; 2 items (Box 4)
  - Bistreich, Alan, 1977; 1 item (Box 4)
  - Black, Cyril, 1985; 1 item (Box 4)
  - Black, Daniel Robert, 1978; 1 item (Box 4)
  - Black, Iva, undated; 1 item (Box 4)
  - Blackwell, Gordon, 1955; 1 item (Box 4)
  - Blake, Betty, 1978; 1 item (Box 4)
  - Blalock, Audrey, 1988; 1 item (Box 4)
  - Blanchette, Estelle, 1990; 1 item (Box 4)
  - Blanton, Smiley, 1955; 1956; 2 items (Box 4)
  - Blatner, Allee and Adam, 1986-1987; 6 items (Box 4)
  - Bleibtren, John, 1968; 1 item (Box 4)
  - Blish, James, 1959; 1 item (Box 4)
  - Bliven, Bruce, 1942; 2 items (Box 4)
  - Bloch, Michael, 1979-1984; 5 items (Box 4)
  - Bloom, Leon, 1977; 1 item (Box 4)
  - Bloomer, Bill, 1978; 1 item (Box 4)
  - Blum, Frances, 1965; 4 items (Box 4)
  - Bluston, Esther, 1969; 1 item (Box 4)
  - Boardman, Philip, 1976-1977; 6 items (Box 4)
  - Boardman, W, 1965; 1 item (Box 4)
  - Boas, Ernst, 1945; 1 item (Box 4)
  - Boas, Franz, 1940; 1942; 2 items (Box 4)
  - Boaz, Noel, 1992; 2 items (Box 4)
  - Bobula, Ida, 1965; 2 items (Box 4)
  - Boesen, Jeanne, 1990; 2 items (Box 4)
  - Bogen, Joseph, 1981; 1 item (Box 4)
  - Bohannan, Laura, 1971-1972; 4 items (Box 4)
  - Bolei, Marvin, 1955; 3 items (Box 4)
  - Bond, Alison, 1971; 1972; 2 items (Box 4)
  - Bonewits, Isaac, 1970; 1 item (Box 4)
  - Bonewitz, R.L, 1993; 2 items (Box 4)
  - Bongiovanni, Alfred, 1961; 1962; 2 items (Box 4)
  - Bonner, John Tyler, 1983; 1 item (Box 4)
  - Bonnet, Muriel, undated; 1 item (Box 4)
  - Boone, Geraldine, 1989; 3 items (Box 4)
  - Boone, Jerry, 1977; 2 items (Box 4)
  - Boorstin, Daniel, 1979; 1 item (Box 4)
  - Booth, Jimmie, 1989-1992; undated; 8 items (Box 4)
  - Booth, V, 1990; 1 item (Box 4)
  - Boothby, Derek, undated; 1 item (Box 4)
  - Bordner, Robert, 1945; 1 item (Box 4)
  - Borg, James, 1978-1980; undated; 17 items (Box 4)
  - Boring, Edwin, 1944-1945; undated; 8 items (Box 4)
  - Bortnick, Barry, 1987; 2 items (Box 4)
  - Bose, N.K, 1961; 1 item (Box 4)